皆さんこんにちは、コーダーのためのディープラーニング、レッスン１へようこそ。
今年で4年目になりますが、これまでとは違った特別なバージョンになっています。
まず第一に、完全にシャットダウンされた初日から生放送でお届けします。
完全なシャットダウンではありませんがサンフランシスコはほぼ完全にシャットダウンしています。
この世界的なパンデミックの真っ只中で ２ヶ月間に渡って 録画する予定です。
もしこのコースで時々少し慌ただしいように見えたら謝罪します。
しかし、このようなことが起きているのが理由です。
もう一つの特別な理由は これを私たちの決定版にしようとしているからです。
長い間続けてきたことで やっと自分たちが何を言ってるのか、わかった気がしてきました。
シルヴァンと私は実際に本を書いて、
ゼロからfastai2というソフトウェアも書きました。
このライブラリについては査読付きの論文も書いています。
ですから、このバージョンのコースは、うまくいけばしばらくは続くと思います。
シラバスはこの本に非常に密接に基づいています。
だから、もしあなたがちゃんと読みたいのであれば、ぜひ買ってください。
そして、「買ってください」と言っているのは、実際にはジュピターノートブックという形で全てが無料で手に入るからです。
これはオライリー・メディアの寛大なご厚意のおかげです。
コースのウェブサイトにアクセス方法が掲載されていますが、
ここにあるfastbookのレポでは全ての内容を読むことができます。
今のところ、ご覧のようにそれは草稿ですが、あなたがこれを読む頃にはそうはなっていないでしょう。
そこで、ここで大きな要望があります。
ジュピターノートブックとして無料で読むことができますが、
Kindleや紙の本などで読むのと比べると便利ではありません。
だから、これをPDFにするのはやめてください。
読むことを目的としたフォーマットにはしないでください。
そもそもの目的はよかったらあなたに買ってもらうことです。
オライリーの寛大さを利用して、タダで貰えないと分かっているものを作るのはやめてください。
実際にはそれが、私たちがこれを提供しているライセンスなのです。
これは主にまともな人間であってくださいとのお願いです。
もし他の誰かがまともな人間ではなく、書籍版を盗んでいるのを見たら、
「そんなことしないでくれ、迷惑だから 」と言ってあげてください。
そして、そんな人にならないようにしましょう。
ということで、どちらにしても、本の中のシラバスに沿って読んでください。
このノートにはいくつかのバージョンがあります。
全部の文章、写真、全てが載っている完全なノートがあります。
私たちは実際にジュピターノートブックを印刷する本にするためのシステムを作ったたのですが、
それがちょっと変な感じに見えることがあります。
例えば、ここに変な表がありますが、
実際の本の中を見てみると、
実際にはちゃんとした表のように見えますよね。
時々変なところが出てきますが、
これは間違いではありません。
本を素敵な本にするための情報を追加するためのものですので、無視してください。
さて「私たち」と言えば、私たちとは誰でしょう？
「私たち」の重要な部分の一つがシルヴァンです。
シルヴァンは本とfastaiバージョン2ライブラリの私の共著者ですので、彼は私の犯罪のパートナーです。
「私たち」のもう一人はレイチェル・トーマスです。
レイチェル、挨拶をしに来てください。
彼女はfastaiの共同設立者です。
こんにちは、私はfastaiの共同創設者です。
そして、あ、低く。
すみません。
私はジェレミーよりも背が高いんです。
そして私はサンフランシスコ大学の応用データ倫理センターの創設ディレクターです。
このコースに参加できることを本当に楽しみにしています。
そして私の声がフォーラムからの質問を聞く声になります。
レイチェルとシルヴァンは、このグループの中で実際に数学を理解している人たちです。
私は単なる哲学の卒業生です。
レイチェルは博士号を持っています。
シルヴァンは数学について10冊の本を書いているので、
もし数学の質問が来たら、私はそれを委託すかもしれません。
でも、この課題をよく理解している人たちと一緒に仕事をする機会があるのは、とても嬉しいことです。
はい、はいレイチェル、
あぁ、ありがとうございます。
レイチェルが言ってたように、彼女が実際の世界クラスの専門知識を持っているのは
データ倫理であり、彼女は応用データ倫理センターの創設ディレクターです。
サンフランシスコ大学です
サンフランシスコ大学ですね、ありがとうございます。
私たちはコースを通してデータ倫理について話します。
なぜなら、私たちはたまたまそれが非常に重要だと考えているからです。
私が一般的にそれらを発表することになりますが、
全体的にはレイチェルの仕事に基づいたものになります。
彼女は実際に何を言っているのかを知っているので。
でも、彼女のおかげで、私も私が話していることを少しは知っています。
それはそれとして。
あなたはここにいるべきでしょうか。
あなたがを理解することにどんな目的があるのか
（私は正しいボタンを押したと思った）
深層学習を理解しようとすることに意味があるのでしょうか？
OK 、あなたは何を・・・あなたはここにいるべきでしょうか。
あなたが深層学習を学んでメリットがありますか？
あなたがあまり頭がよくないですか？
または十分高速なコンピューターを持っていないですか？、などなど。
それは多くの人々が私たちに言ってくることです。
彼らは、博士号を持ったチームとGPUを搭載した大規模なデータセンターが必要だと言っています。
そうでなければ無意味だと。
心配しないでください、それは全く真実ではありません。
真実からこれ以上離れたものはありません。
実際、大多数の世界的な研究や世界的な産業プロジェクトの多くは、
fastaiの卒業生やfastaiライブラリを使ったプロジェクトや他の場所から生まれたもので、
大学院レベルの技術的な専門知識を持たない人たちから、
数十、数百のデータポイントを使って単一のGPUで作られたものです。
私はといえば大学レベルの専門知識もありません。
私は哲学部です。
しかし、ディープラーニングを使って素晴らしいことをするためには、
たくさんの数学は必要ないし、たくさんのデータも必要ないし、
高価なコンピュータも必要ないという明確な実証的証拠がたくさんあります。
だから我々と一緒に我慢して付いてきてみてください。
あなたは大丈夫です。
このコースを受けるには コードを書く必要があります。
できればPythonでコードを書く方法を 知っていることが望ましいです。
他の言語をやったことがあれば Pythonを学ぶことができます。
もしあなたがこれまでにやったことのある言語がMatlabのようなもので、
スクリプトのようなものを使ったことがあるのであれば、少し難しく感じるかもしれません。
しかし、それでいいんです。
頑張ってください。
Pythonはどんどん学習していけばいいのです。
深層学習を学ぶ意味はありますか？
何かディープラーニングの得意なことはありますか？
もしあなたが脳を作りたいと思っているのであれば、それはAGIです。
なのでこのコースがあなたをの役に立つとは約束できません。
AGIは 人工知能（Artificial General Intelligence）の略です。
ありがとうございます。
しかし私が言えることは これらの分野のすべてにおいて 少なくとも多くのバージョンでは
ディープラーニングが最もよく知られたアプローチであるということです。
ですから、これが有用なツールであるかどうかは、現時点では推測ではありません。
たくさんの、たくさんの、たくさんの、たくさんの場所で役に立つツールなのです。
極めて有用なツールです。
そして、これらの多くのケースでは、人間のパフォーマンスと同等かそれ以上であるのです。
（少なくとも、この種の分野で人間が行うことのいくつかの特定の狭い定義によると）
ディープラーニングは非常に素晴らしいものです。
ここでビデオを一時停止して、興味がありそうなものをいくつかピックアップしてみてください。
そしてそのキーワードとディープラーニングをGoogleで検索すれば、
たくさんの論文や事例などが見つかるはずです。
ディープラーニングは、ニューラルネットワークの背景から来ています。
見ての通り、ディープラーニングはニューラルネットワーク学習の一種です。
深いものです。
それが何を意味するのかは後ほど正確に説明します。
そして、ニューラルネットワークは確かに新しいものではありません。
少なくとも1943年までさかのぼります。
マックロックとピッツが 人工ニューロンの数学モデルを作成した時です。
そして、それがどこに到達するかについて非常に期待されました。
50年代には、フランク・ローゼンブラットが、その上に数学モデルを構築しました。
彼は基本的に、その数学モデルに微妙な変更を加えました。
そして彼は、これらの微妙な変更で、
「人間の訓練や制御なしに 周囲の環境を看取、認識、識別できる機械の誕生を 目撃することができる」
と考えました。
そして彼はこの驚異的なものの開発を監督したのです。
コーネル大学のマーク１パーセプトロンです
この写真は１９６１年だったと思います。
ありがたいことに今日では、ニューラルネットワークを構築するために、
ニューロンからニューロンへ（人工ニューロンから人工ニューロンへ）配線をを走らせる必要はありません。
しかし、多くの接続が行われているという考えが見えてきます。
このコースでは、接続（コネクション）という言葉をよく耳にするでしょう。
それはここからきています。
それから、私たちは最初のAIの冬を迎えました。
これは、MITのマービン・ミンスキー教授とパパートが ローゼンブラットの発明について
パーセプトロンという本を書きました。その中で 彼らが指摘したのは、
これらの人工ニューロンデバイスの単一の層は、実際にはいくつかの重要なことを
学ぶことができないということです。
ブール演算子のXOR演算子のような簡単なものを学ぶことは不可能でした。
同じ本の中で、彼らは、人工ニューロン装置を何層にも重ねて使えば、
実際に問題が解決することを示しています。
でも人々は無視 - 本のその部分に気づかなかったのです。
そして、制限にだけ気付き、人々は基本的にニューラルネットワークは
どこにも行かないと決めつけてしまいました。
そして何十年もの間、それらはほとんど姿を消してしまいました。
ある意味で1986年までは。
その間にいろいろなことがありましたが、1986年に大きなことがありました。
MITが「並列分散処理」という本を出版、2巻に分けてシリーズ化したものです。
その中で、並列分散処理（Parallel Distributed Processing）と呼ばれるものを説明していました。
並列分散処理とは、たくさんの処理装置と、アクティベーションと、出力機能と、
接続性のパターンと、伝播ルールと、活性化ルール、
学習ルールを持った処理ユニットが、環境の中で動作しているというものです。
そして、これらの要件を満たすものが、どのようにして理論的にはあらゆる種類の
驚くべき仕事をすることができるのかを説明しました。
これは、多くの、多くの研究者が協力して取り組んだ結果です。
このプロジェクトにはグループ全体が関わっていて、それがこの非常に重要な
本につながったのです。
そして、私にとって興味深いのは、このコースを受講した後に、
この写真を見ていただければ、私たちがまさにこのようなことをしていることがわかると思います。
私たちが学んでいることは、これらの8つのことをどのようにするかということです。
環境が含まれているのは興味深いことですが、これはデータサイエンティストが
無視することが多いからです。
モデルを構築し、それを訓練し、何かを学習しました。
それがどのようなコンテキストで動作するのか？
それについては、次のレッスンでも度々お話しします。
そして80年代に、これがリリースされた後、人々は第二層のニューロンを構築し始めました。
ミンスキーの問題を回避するためです。
And in fact, it was shown, that it was mathematically
provable, that by adding that one extra layer
of neurons, it was enough to allow any mathematical
model to be approximated to any level of accuracy,
with these neural networks.
And so that was like the exact opposite of
the Minsky thing.
That was like: “Hey there's nothing we can't
do.
Provably there's nothing we can't do.”
And so that was kind of when I started getting
involved in neural networks.
So I was - a little bit later.
I guess I was getting involved in the early
90s.
And they were very widely used in industry.
I was using them for very boring things like
targeted marketing for retail banks.
They tended to be big companies with lots
of money that were using them.
And it certainly though was true that often
the networks were too big or slow to be useful.
They were certainly useful for some things,
but they - you know they never felt to me
like they were living up to the promise for
some reason.
Now what I didn't know, and nobody I personally
met knew was that actually there were researchers
that had shown 30 years ago that to get practical
good performance, you need more layers of
neurons.
Even though mathematically, theoretically,
you can get as accurate as you want with just
one extra layer.
To do it with good performance, you need more
layers.
So when you add more layers to a neural network
you get deep learning.
So deep doesn't mean anything like mystical.
It just means more layers.
More layers than just adding the one extra
one.
So thanks to that, neural nets are now living
up to their potential.
As we saw in that like what's deep learning
good at thing.
So we could now say that Rosenblatt was right.
We have a machine that's capable of perceiving,
recognising and identifying its surroundings
without any human training or control.
That is - That's definitely true.
I don't think there's anything controversial
about that statement based on the current
technology.
So we're gonna be learning how to do that.
We're gonna be learning how to do that in
exactly the opposite way, of probably all
of the other math and technical education
you've had.
We are not gonna start with a two-hour lesson
about the sigmoid function or a study of linear
algebra or a refresher course on calculus.
And the reason for that, is that people who
study how to teach and learn have found that
is not the right way to do it for most people.
For most people - So we work a lot based on
the work of Professor David Perkins from Harvard
and others who work at similar things, who
talk about this idea of playing the whole
game.
And so playing the whole game is like it's
based on the sports analogy if you're gonna
teach somebody baseball.
You don't take them out into a classroom and
start teaching them about the physics of a
parabola, and how to stitch a ball, and a
three-part history of 100 years of baseball
politics, and then 10 years later, you let
them watch a game.
And then 20 years later, you let them play
a game.
Which is kind of like how math education is
being done, right?
Instead with baseball, step one is to say,
hey, let's go and watch some baseball.
What do you think?
That was fun, right?
See that guy there...he took a run there…before
the other guy throws a ball over there...hey,
you want to try having a hit?
Okay, so you're going to hit the ball, and
then I have to try to catch it, then he has
to run,run,run over there...and so from step
one, you are playing the whole game.
And just to add to that, when people start,
they often may not have a full team, or be
playing the full nine innings, but they still
have a sense of what the game is, a kind of
a big picture idea.
So, there is lots and lots of reasons that
this helps most human beings, (though) not
everybody, right?
There's a small percentage of people who like
to build things up from the foundations and
the principles, and not surprisingly, they
are massively overrepresented in a university
setting, because the people who get to be
academics are the people who thrive with,
(according) to me, the upside down way of
how things are taught.
But outside of universities most people learn
best in this top-down way, where you start
with the full context.
So step number two in the seven principles,
and I'm only going to mention the first three,
is to make the game worth playing.
Which is like, if you're playing baseball,
you have a competition.
You know, you score, you try and win, you
bring together teams from around the community
and you have people try to beat each other.
And you have leaderboards, like who's got
the highest number of runs or whatever.
So this is all about making sure that the
thing you're doing, you're doing it properly.
You're making it the whole thing, you're providing
the context and the interest.
So, for the fastai approach to learning deep
learning, what this means is that today we're
going to train models end to end.
We're going to actually train models, and
they won't just be crappy models.
They will be state-of-the-art world-class
models from today, and we can try to have
you build your own state-of-the-art world-class
models from either today or next lesson, depending
on how things go.
Then, number three in the seven principles
from Harvard is, work on the hard parts.
Which is kind of like this idea of practice,
deliberate practice.
Work on the hard parts means that you don't
just swing a bat at a ball every time, you
know, you go out and just muck around.
You train properly, you find the bit that
you are the least good at, you figure out
where the problems are, you work damn hard
at it.
So, in the deep learning context, that means
that we do not dumb things down.
Right?
By the end of the course, you will have done
the calculus.
You will have done the linear algebra.
You will have done the software engineering
of the code, right?
You will be practicing these things which
are hard, so it requires tenacity and commitment.
But hopefully, you'll understand why it matters
because before you start practicing something
you'll know why you need that thing because
you'll be using it.
Like to make your model better, you'll have
to understand that concept first.
So for those of you used to a traditional
university environment, this is gonna feel
pretty weird and a lot of people say: “that
they regret (you know after a year of studying
fastai) that they spent too much time studying
theory, and not enough time training models
and writing code.
That's the kind of like, the number one piece
of feedback we get from people who say, “I
wish I've done things differently.”
It's that.
So please try to, as best as you can, since
you're here, follow along with this approach.
We are gonna be using a software stack - Sorry
Rachel.
Yes?
I just need to say one more thing about the
approach.
I think since, so many of us spent so many
years with the traditional educational approach
of bottom-up, that this can feel very uncomfortable
at first.
I still feel uncomfortable with it sometimes,
even though I'm committed to the idea.
And that, some of it is also having to catch
yourself and being okay with not knowing the
details.
Which I think can feel very unfamiliar, or
even wrong when you're kind of new to that.
Of like: “Oh wait, I'm using something and
I don't understand every underlying detail.”
But you kind of have to trust that we're gonna
get to those details later.
So I can't empathise because I did not spend
lots of time doing that.
But I will tell you this - teaching this way
is very, very, very hard.
And I very often find myself jumping back
into a foundations first approach.
Because it's just so easy to be like: “Oh
you need to know this.
You need to know this.
You need to do this.
And then you can know this.”
That's so much easier to teach.
So I do find this much much more challenging
to teach, but hopefully it's worth it.
We spent a long long time figuring out how
to get deep learning into this format.
But one of the things that helps us here,
is the software we have available.
If you haven't used Python before - it's ridiculously
flexible and expressive and easy-to-use language.
We have plenty of bits about it we don't love
but on the whole we love the overall thing.
And we think it's - Most importantly, the
vast, vast, vast majority of deep learning
practitioners and researchers are using Python.
On top of Python, there are two libraries
that most folks are using today; PyTorch and
TensorFlow.
There's been a very rapid change here.
TensorFlow was what we were teaching until
a couple of years ago.
It's what everyone was using until a couple
of years ago.
It got super bogged down, basically TensorFlow
got super bogged down.
This other software called PyTorch came along
that was much easier to use and much more
useful for researchers and within the last
12 months, the percentage of papers at major
conferences that uses PyTorch has gone from
20% to 80% and vice versa, those that use
TensorFlow have gone on from 80% to 20%.
So basically all the folks that are actually
building the technology were all using, are
now using, PyTorch and you know industry moves
a bit more slowly but in the next year or
two you will probably see a similar thing
in industry.
Now, the thing about PyTorch is it's super
super flexible and really is designed for
flexibility and developer friendliness, certainly
not designed for beginner friendliness and
it's not designed for what we say, it doesn't
have higher level API's, by which I mean there
isn't really things to make it easy to build
stuff quickly using PyTorch.
So to deal with that issue, we have a library
called fastai that sits on top of PyTorch.
Fastai is the most popular higher level API
for PyTorch.
It is, because our courses are so popular,
some people are under the mistaken impression
that fastai is designed for beginners or for
teaching.
It is designed for beginners and teaching,
as well as practitioners in industry and researchers.
The way we do this makes sure that it's, that
it's the best API for all of those people
as we use something called a layered API and
so there's a peer-reviewed paper that Sylvain
and I wrote that described how we did that
and for those of you that are software engineers,
it will not be at all unusual or surprising.
It's just totally standard software engineering
practices, but they are practices that were
not followed in any deep learning library
we had seen.
Just basically lots of re-factoring and decoupling
and so by using that approach, it's allowed
us to build something which you can do super
low-level research, you can do state-of-the-art
production models and you can do kind of super
easy, beginner, but beginner world-class models.
So that's the basic software stack, there's
other pieces of software we will be learning
about along the way.
But the main thing I think to mention here
is it actually doesn't matter.
If you learn this software stack and then
at work you need to use TensorFlow and Keras,
you will be able to switch in less than a
week.
Lots and lots of students have done that,
it's never been a problem.
The important thing is to learn the concepts
and so we're going to focus on those concepts
and by using an API which minimizes the amount
of boilerplate you have to use, it means you
can focus on the bits that are important.
The actual lines of code will correspond much
more to the actual concepts you are implementing.
You are going to need a GPU machine.
A GPU is a Graphics Processing Unit, and specifically,
you need an Nvidia GPU.
Other brands of GPU just aren't well supported
by any Deep Learning libraries.
Please don't buy one.
If you already have one you probably shouldn't
use it.
Instead you should use one of the platforms
that we have already got set up for you.
It's just a huge distraction to be spending
your time doing, like, system administration
on a GPU machine and installing drivers and
blah blah blah.
And run it on Linux.
Please.
That's what everybody's doing, not just us,
everybody's running it on Linux.
Make life easy for yourself.
It's hard enough to learn Deep Learning without
having to do it in a way that you are learning,
you know, all kinds of arcane hardware support
issues.
There's a lot of free options available and
so, please, please use them.
If you're using an option that is not free
don't forget to shut down your instance.
So what's gonna be happening is you gonna
be spinning up a server that lives somewhere
else in the world, and you're gonna be connecting
to it from your computer and training and
running and building models.
Just because you close your browser window
doesn't mean your server stops running on
the whole.
Right?
So don't forget to shut it down because otherwise
you're paying for it.
Colab, is a great system which is free.
There's also a paid subscription version of
it.
Be careful with Colab.
Most of the other systems we recommend save
your work for you automatically and you can
come back to it at any time.
Colab doesn't.
So be sure to check out the Colab platform
thread on the forums, to learn about that.
So, I mention the forums...
The forums are really, really important because
that is where all of the discussion and set
up and everything happens.
So for example if you want help with setup
here.
You know there is a setup help thread and
you can find out, you know, how to best set
up Colab, and you can see discussions about
it and you can ask questions, and please remember
to search before you ask your question, right?
Because it's probably been asked before, unless
you're one of the very, very earliest people
who are doing the course.
So, once you…
So, step one is to get your server set up
by just following the instructions from the
forums or from the course website.
And the course website will have lots of step-by-step
instructions for each platform.
They will vary in price, they will vary in
speed, they will vary in availability, and
so forth.
Once you are finished following those instructions
The last step of those instructions will end
up showing you something like this: a course
v4 folder, so a version four of our course.
By the time you see this video, this is likely
to have more stuff in it, but it will have
an NB's standing for notebooks folder.
So you can click on that, and that will show
you all of the notebooks for the course.
What I want you to do is scroll bottom and
find the one called app Jupyter.
Click on that, and this is where you can start
learning about Jupyter notebook.
What's Jupyter Notebook?
Jupyter Notebook is something where you can
start typing things, and press Shift-Enter,
and it will give you an answer.
And so the thing you're typing is python code,
and the thing that comes out is a result of
that code.
And so you can put in anything in python.
X equals three times four.
X plus one, and as you can see, it displays
a result anytime there's a result to display.
So for those of you that have done a bit of
coding before, you will recognise this as
a REPL.
R-E-P-L, read, evaluate, print, loop.
Most languages have some kind of REPL.
The Jupyter notebook REPL is particularly
interesting, because it has things like headings,
graphical outputs, interactive multimedia.
It's a really astonishing piece of software.
It's won some really big awards.
I would have thought the most widely used
REPL, outside of shells like bash.
It's a very powerful system.
We love it.
We've written our whole book in it, we've
written the entire FASTAI library with it,
we do all our teaching with it.
It's extremely unfamiliar to people who have
done most of their work in IDE.
You should expect it to feel as awkward as
perhaps the first time you moved from a GUI
to a command line.
It's different.
So if you're not familiar with REPL-based
systems, it's gonna feel super weird.
But stick with it, because it really is great.
The kind of model going on here is that, this
webpage I'm looking at, is letting me type
in things for a server to do, and show me
the results of computations a server is doing.
So the server is off somewhere else.
It's not running on my computer right?
The only thing running on the computer is
this webpage.
But as I do things, so for example if I say
X equals X times three.
This is updating the servers state.
There's this state.
It's like what's currently the value of X
and so I can find out, now X is something
different.
So you can see, when I did this line here,
it didn't change the earlier X plus one, right?
So that means that when you look at a Jupyter
notebook, it's not showing you the current
state of your server.
It's just showing you what that state was,
at the time that you printed that thing out.
It's just like if you use a shell like bash.
And you type “ls”.
And then you delete a file.
That earlier “ls” you printed doesn't
go back and change.
That's kind of how REPLs generally work.
Including this one.
Jupyter notebook has two modes.
One is edit mode, which is when I click on
a cell and I get a flashing cursor and I can
move left and right and type.
Right?
There's not very many keyboard shortcuts to
this mode.
One useful one is “control” or “command”
+ “/”. Which will comment and uncomment.
The main one to know is “shift” + “enter”
to actually run the cell.
At that point there is no flashing cursor
anymore.
And that means that I'm now in command mode.
Not edit mode.
So as I go up and down, I'm selecting different
cells.
So in command mode as we move around, we're
now selecting cells.
And there are now lots of keyboard shortcuts
you can use.
So if you hit “H” you can get a list of
them.
That, for example - And you'll see that they're
not on the whole, like “control” or “command”
with something they're just the letter on
its own.
So if you use like Vim, you'll be more familiar
with this idea.
So for example if I hit “C” to copy and
“V” to paste.
Then it copies the cell.
Or “X” to cut it.
“A” to add a new cell above.
And then I can press the various number keys,
to create a heading.
So number two will create a heading level
II.
And as you can see, I can actually type formatted
text not just code.
The formatted text I type is in Markdown.
Like so.
My numbered one work.
There you go.
So that's in Markdown.
If you haven't used Markdown before, it's
a super super useful way to write formatted
text.
That is used very, very, very widely.
So learn it because it's super handy.
And you need it for Jupiter.
So when you look at our book notebooks.
For example, you can see an example of all
the kinds of formatting and code and stuff
here.
So you should go ahead and go through the
“app_jupyter”.
And you can see here how you can create plots
for example.
And create lists of things.
And import libraries.
And display pictures and so forth.
If you wanna create a new notebook, you can
just go “New” “Python 3” and that
creates a new notebook.
Which by default is just called “Untitled”
so you can then rename it to give it whatever
name you like.
And so then you'll now see that, in the list
here, “newname”.
The other thing to know about Jupiter is that
it's a nice easy way to jump into a terminal
if you know how to use a terminal.
You certainly don't have to for this course
at least for the first bit.
If I go to a new terminal, You can see here
I have a terminal.
One thing to note is for the notebooks are
attached to a Github repository.
If you haven't used Github before that's fine.
but basically they're attached to a server
where from time to time we will update the
notebooks on it.
And we will see you'll see on the course website,
in the forum we tell you how to make sure
you have the most recent versions.
When you grab our most recent version you
don't want to conflict with or overwrite your
changes.
So as you start experimenting it's not a bad
idea to like select a notebook and click duplicate
and then start doing your work in the copy.
And that way when you get an update of our
latest course materials, it's not gonna interfere
with the experiments you've been running.
So there are two important repositories to
know about.
One is the fast book repository which we saw
earlier, which is kind of the full book with
all the outputs and pros and everything.
And then the other one is the course V4 repository.
And here is the exact same notebook from the
course V4 repository.
And for this one we remove all of the pros
and all of the pictures and all of the outputs
and just leave behind the headings and the
code.
In this case you can see some outputs because
I just ran that code, most of it.
There won't be any.
No, No, I guess we have left outputs.
I'm not sure to keep that or not.
So you may or may not see the outputs.
So the idea with this is.
This is properly the version that you want
to be experimenting with.
Because it kind of forces you to think about
like what's going on as you do each step,
rather than just reading it and running it
without thinking.
We kind of want you to do it in a small bare
environment in which you thinking about like
what did the book say why was this happening
and if you forget anything then you kind of
go back to the book.
The other thing to mention is both the course
V4 version and the fast book version at the
end have a questionnaire.
And a quite a few folks have told us you know
that in amongst the reviewers and stuff that
they actually read the questionnaire first.
We spent many, many weeks writing the questionnaires,
Sylvain and I.
And the reason for that is because we try
to think about like what do we want you to
take away from each notebook.
So you kind of read the questionnaire first.
You can find out what are the things we think
are important.
What are the things you should know before
you move on.
So rather than having like a summary section
at the end saying at the end of this you should
know, blah blah blah, we instead have a questionnaire
to do the same thing, so please make sure
you do the questionnaire before you move onto
the next chapter.
You don't have to get everything right, and
most of the time answering the questions is
as simple as going back to that part of the
notebook and reading the prose, but if you've
missed something, like do go back and read
it because these are the things we are assuming
you know.
So if you don't know these things before you
move on, it could get frustrating.
Having said that, if you get stuck after trying
a couple of times, do move onto the next chapter,
do two or three more chapters and then come
back.
maybe by the time you've done a couple more
chapters, you know, you will get some more
perspective.
We try to re-explain things multiple times
in different ways, so it's okay if you tried
and you get stuck, then you can try moving
on.
Alright, so, let's try running the first part
of the notebook.
So here we are in 01 intro, so this is chapter
1 and here is our first cell.
So I click on the cell and by default, actually,
there will be a header in the toolbar as you
can see.
You can turn them on or off.
I always leave them off myself and so to run
this cell, you can either click on the play,
the run button or as I mentioned, you can
hit shift enter.
So for this one this i'll just click and as
you can see this star appears, so this says
I'm running and now you can see this progress
bar popping up and that is going to take a
few seconds and so as it runs to print out
some results.
Don't expect to get exactly the same results
as us, there is some randomness involved in
training a model, and that's okay.
Don't expect to get exactly the same time
as us.
If this first cell takes more than five minutes
unless you have a really old GPU that is probably
a bad sign.
You might want to hop on the forums and figure
out what's going wrong or maybe it only has
windows which really doesn't work very well
for this moment.
Don't worry that we don't know what all the
code does yet.
We are just making sure that we can train
a model . So here we are, it's finished running
and so as you can see, it's printed out some
information and in this case it's showing
me that there is an error rate of 0.005 at
doing something.
What is the something it's doing?
Well, what it's doing here is it's actually
grabbing a dataset, we call the pets dataset,
which is a dataset of pictures of cats and
dogs.
And it's trying to figure out; which ones
are cats and which ones are dogs.
And as you can see, after about well less
than a minute, it's able to do that with a
0.5% error rate.
So it can do it pretty much perfectly.
So we've trained our first model.
We have no idea how.
We don't know what we were doing.
But we have indeed trained our model.
So that's a good start.
And as you can see, we can train models pretty
quickly on a single computer.
Which you know - Many of which you can get
for free.
One more thing to mention is, if you have
a Mac - doesn't matter whether you have Windows
or Mac or Linux in terms of what's running
in the browser.
But if you have a Mac, please don't try to
use that GPU.
Mac's actually - Apple doesn't even support
Nvidia GPUs anymore.
So that's really not gonna be a great option.
So stick with Linux.
It will make life much easier for you.
Right, actually the first thing we should
do is actually try it out.
So if - I claim we've trained a model that
can pick cats from dogs.
Let's make sure we can.
So let's - Check out this cell.
This is interesting.
Right?
We've created a widgets dot file upload object
and displayed it.
And this is actually showing us a clickable
button.
So as I mentioned this is an unusual REPL.
We can even create GUIs, in this REPL.
So if I click on this file upload.
And I can pick “cat”.
There we go.
And I can now turn that uploaded data into
an image.
There's a cat.
And now I can do predict, and it's a cat.
With a 99.96% probability.
So we can see we have just uploaded an image
that we've picked out.
So you should try this.
Right?
Grab a picture of a cat.
Find one from the Internet or go and take
a picture of one yourself.
And make sure that you get a picture of a
cat.
This is something which can recognise photos
of cats, not line drawings of cats.
And so as we'll see, in this course.
These kinds of models can only learn from
the kinds of information you give it.
And so far we've only given it, as you'll
discover, photos of cats.
Not anime cats, not drawn cats, not abstract
representations of cats but just photos.
So we're now gonna look at; what's actually
happened here?
And you'll see at the moment, I am not getting
some great information here.
If you see this, in your notebooks, you'll
have to go: file, trust notebook.
And that just tells Jupiter that it's allowed
to run the code necessary to display things,
to make sure there isn't any security problems.
And so you'll now see the outputs.
Sometimes you'll actually see some weird code
like this.
This is code that actually creates outputs.
So sometimes we hide that code.
Sometimes we show it.
So generally speaking, you can just ignore
the stuff like that and focus on what comes
out.
So I'm not gonna go through these.
Instead I'm gonna have a look at it - same
thing over here on the slides.
So what we're doing here is; we're doing machine
learning.
Deep learning is a kind of machine learning.
What is machine learning?
Machine learning is, just like regular programming,
it's a way to get computers to do something.
But in this case, it's pretty hard to understand
how you would use regular programming to recognise
dog photos from cat photos.
How do you kind of create the loops and the
variable assignments and the conditionals
to create a program that recognises dogs vs
cats in photos.
It's super hard.
Super super hard.
So hard, that until kind of the deep learning
era, nobody really had a model that was remotely
accurate at this apparently easy task.
Because we can't write down the steps necessary.
So normally, you know, we write down a function
that takes some inputs and goes through our
program.
Produces some results.
So this general idea where the program is
something that we write (the steps).
Doesn't seem to work great for things like
recognising pictures.
So back in 1949, somebody named Arthur Samuel
started trying to figure out a way to solve
problems like recognising pictures of cats
and dogs.
And in 1962, he described a way of doing this.
Well first of all he described the problem:
“Programming a computer for these kinds
of computations is at best a difficult task.
Because of the need to spell out every minute
step of the process in exasperating detail.
Computers are giant morons which all of us
coders totally recognise.”
So he said, okay, let's not tell the computer
the exact steps, but let's give it examples
of a problem to solve and figure out how to
solve it itself.
And so, by 1961 he had built a checkers program
that had beaten the Connecticut state champion,
not by telling it the steps to take to play
checkers, but instead by doing this, which
is: “arrange for an automatic means of testing
the effectiveness of a weight assignment in
terms of actual performance and a mechanism
for altering the weight assignment so as to
maximise performance.”
This sentence is the key thing.
And it's a pretty tricky sentence so you can
spend some time on it.
The basic idea is this; instead of saying
inputs to a program and then outputs.
Let's have inputs to a - let's call the program
now model.
It is the same basic idea.
Inputs to a model and results.
And then we're gonna have a second thing called
weights.
And so the basic idea is that this model is
something that creates outputs based not only
on, for example, the state of a checkers board,
but also based on some set of weights or parameters
that describe how that model is going to work.
So the idea is, if we could, like, enumerate
all the possible ways of playing checkers,
and then kind of describe each of those ways
using some set of parameters or what Samuel
called weights.
Then if we had a way of checking how effective
a current weight assignment is in terms of
actual performance, in other words, does that
particular enumeration of a strategy for playing
checkers end up winning or losing games, and
then a way to alter the weight assignment
so as to maximise the performance.
So then oh let's try increasing or decreasing
each one of those weights one at a time to
find out if there is a slightly better way
of playing checkers and then do that lots
of lots of times then eventually such a procedure
could be made entirely automatic and then
the machine so programmed would learn from
its experience so this little paragraph is,
is the thing.
This is machine learning a way of creating
programs such that they learn, rather than
programmed.
So if we had such a thing, then we would basically
now have something that looks like this: you
have inputs and weights again going into a
model, creating results, i.e. you won or you
lost, and then a measurement of performance.
So remember that was this key step and then
the second key step is a way to update the
weights based on the measured performance
and then you could look through this process
and create a) train a machine learning model
so this is the abstract idea.
So after it ran for a while, right, it's come
up with a set of weights which it's pretty
good, right, we can now forget the way it
was trained and we have something that is
just like this, right, except the word program
is now replaced with the word model.
So a trained model can be used just like any
other computer program.
So the idea is we are building a computer
program not by putting up the steps necessary
to do the task, but by training it to learn
to do the task at the end of which it's just
another program and so this is what's called
inference right is using a trained model as
a program to do a task such as playing checkers
so machine learning is training programs developed
by allowing a computer to learn from its experience
rather than through manually coding.
Ok how would you do this for image recognition,
what is that model and that set of weights
such that as we vary them it could get better
and better at recognising cats versus dogs,
I mean for checkers
It's not too hard to imagine how you could
kind of enumerate, depending on different
kinds of “how far away the opponent's piece
is from your piece,” what should you do
in that situation.
How should you weigh defensive versus aggressive
strategies, blah blah blah.
Not at all obvious how you do that for image
recognition.
So what we really want, is some function in
here which is so flexible that there is a
set of weights that could cause it to do anything.
A real--like the world's most flexible possible
function--and turns out that there is such
a thing.
It's a neural network.
So we'll be describing exactly what that mathematical
function is in the coming lessons.
To use it, it actually doesn't really matter
what the mathematical function is.
It's a function which is, we say, “parameterised”
by some set of weights by which I mean, as
I give it a different set of weights it does
a different task, and it can actually do any
possible task: something called the universal
approximation theorem tells us that mathematically
provably, this functional form can solve any
problem that is solvable to any level of accuracy.
If you just find the right set of weights.
Which is kind of restating what we described
earlier in that, like, how do we deal with
Minsky (the Marvin Minsky) problem so neural
networks are so flexible that if you could
find the right set of weights they can solve
any problem including “Is this a car or
is this dog.”
So that means you need to focus your effort
on the process of training that is finding
good weights, good weight assignments to use
Samuel's terminology.
So how do you do that?
We want a completely general way to do this--to
update the weights based on some measure of
performance, such as how good is it at recognising
cats versus dogs.
And luckily it turns out such a thing exists!
And that thing is called stochastic gradient
descent (or SGD).
Again, we'll look at exactly how it works,
we'll build it ourselves from scratch, but
for now we don't have to worry about it.
I will tell you this, though, neither SGD
nor neural nets are at all mathematically
complex.
They nearly entirely are addition and multiplication.
The trick is it just a lot of them--like billions
of them--so many more than we can intuitively
grasp.
They can do extraordinarily powerful things,
but they're not rocket science at all.
They are not complex things, and we will see
exactly how they work.
So that's the Arthur Samuel version, right?
Nowadays we don't use quite the same terminology,
but we use exactly the same idea.
So that function that sits in the middle,
we call an architecture.
An architecture is the function that we're
adjusting the weights to get it to do something.
That's the architecture, that's the functional
form of the model.
Sometimes people say model to mean architecture,
so don't let that confuse you too much.
But, really the right word is architecture.
We don't call them weights; we call them parameters.
Weights has a specific meaning- it's quite
a particular kind of parameter.
The things that come out of the model, the
architecture with the parameters, we call
them predictions.
The predictions are based on two kinds of
inputs: independent variables that's the data,
like the pictures of the cats and dogs, and
dependent variables also known as labels,
which is like the thing saying “this is
a cat”, “this is a dog”, “this is
a cat”.
So, that's your inputs.
So, the results are predictions.
The measure of performance, to use Arthur
Samuel's word, is known as the loss.
So, the loss is being calculated from the
labels on the predictions and then there's
the update back to the parameters.
Okay, so, this is the same picture as we saw,
but just putting in the words that we use
today.
So, this picture- if you forget, if I say
these are the parameters of this used for
this architecture to create a model- you can
go back and remind yourself what they mean.
What are the parameters?
What are the predictions?
What is the loss?
Okay, the loss of some function that measures
the performance of the model in such a way
that we can update the parameters.
So, it's important to note that deep learning
and machine learning are not magic, right?
The model can only be created where you have
data showing you examples of the thing that
you're trying to learn about.
It can only learn to operate on the patterns
that you've seen in the input used to train
it, right?
So, if we don't have any line drawings of
cats and dogs, then there's never going to
be an update to the parameters that makes
the architecture and so the architect and
the parameters together is the model.
So, to say the model, that makes the model
better at predicting line drawings of cats
and dogs because they just, they never received
those weight updates because they never received
those inputs.
Notice also that this learning approach only
ever creates predictions.
It doesn't tell you what to do about it.
That's going to be very important when we
think about things like a recommendation system
of like “what product do we recommend to
somebody”?
Well, I don't know- we don't do that, right?
We can predict what somebody will say about
a product we've shown them, but we're not
creating actions.
We're creating predictions.
That's a super important difference to recognize.
It's not enough just to have examples of input
data like pictures of dogs and cats.
We can't do anything without labels.
And so very often, organisations say: “we
don't have enough data”.
Most of the time they mean: “we don't have
enough labelled data”.
Because if a company is trying to do something
with deep learning, often it's because they're
trying to automate or improve something they're
already doing.
Which means by definition they have data about
that thing or a way to capture data about
that thing.
Cus they're doing it.
Right?
But often the tricky part is labelling it.
So for example in medicine.
If you're trying to build a model for radiology.
You can almost certainly get lots of medical
images about just about anything you can think
of.
But it might be very hard to label them according
to malignancy of a tumour or according to
whether or not meningioma is present or whatever,
because these kinds of labels are not necessarily
captured in a structured way, at least in
the US medical system.
So that's an important distinction that really
impacts your kind of strategy.
So then a model, as we saw from the PDP book,
a model operates in an environment.
Right?
You roll it out and you do something with.
And so then, this piece of that kind of PDP
framework is super important.
Right?
You have a model that's actually doing something.
For example, you've built a predictive policing
model that predicts (doesn't recommend actions)
it predicts where an arrest might be made.
This is something a lot of jurisdictions in
the US are using.
Now it's predicting that, based on data and
based on labelled data.
And in this case it's actually gonna be using
(in the US) for example data where, I think,
depending on whether you're black or white,
black people in the US, I think, get arrested
something like seven times more often for
say marijuana possession than whites.
Even though the actual underlying amount of
marijuana use is about the same in the two
populations.
So if you start with biased data and you build
a predictive policing model.
Its prediction will say: “oh you will find
somebody you can arrest here” based on some
biased data.
So then, law enforcement officers might decide
to focus their police activity on the areas
where those predictions are happening.
As a result of which they'll find more people
to arrest.
And then they'll use that, to put it back
into the model.
Which will now find: “oh there's even more
people we should be arresting in the black
neighbourhoods” and thus it continues.
So this would be an example of how a model
interacting with its environment creates something
called a positive feedback loop.
Where the more a model is used, the more biased
the data becomes, making the model even more
biased and so forth.
So one of the things to be super careful about
with machine learning is; recognising how
that model is actually being used and what
kinds of things might happen as a result of
that.
I was just going to add that this is an example
of proxies because here arrest is being used
as a proxy for crime, and I think that pretty
much in all cases, the data that you actually
have is a proxy for some value that you truly
care about.
And that difference between the proxy and
the actual value often ends up being significant.
Thanks, Rachel.
That's a really important point.
Okay, so let's finish off by looking at what's
going on with this code.
So the code we ran is, basically -- one, two,
three, four, five, six -- lines of code.
So the first line of code is an import line.
So in Python you can't use an external library
until you import from it.
Normally in place, people import just the
functions and classes that they need from
the library.
But Python does provide a convenient facility
where you can import everything from a module,
which is by putting a start there.
Most of the time, this is a bad idea.
Because, by default, the way Python works
is that if you say import star, it doesn't
only import the things that are interesting
and important in the library you're trying
to get something from.
But it also imports things from all the libraries
it used, and all the libraries they used,
and you end up kind of exploding your namespace
in horrible ways and causing all kinds of
bugs.
Because fastai is designed to be used in this
REPL environment where you want to be able
to do a lot of quick rapid prototyping, we
actually spent a lot of time figuring out
how to avoid that problem so that you can
import star safely.
So, whether you do this or not, is entirely
up to you.
But rest assured that if you import star from
a fastai library, it's actually been explicitly
designed in a way that you only get the bits
that you actually need.
One thing to mention is in the video you see
it's called “fastai2.”
That's because we're recording this video
using a prerelease version.
By the time you are watching the online, the
MOOC, version of this, the 2 will be gone.
Something else to mention is, there are, as
I speak, four main predefined applications
in fastai, being vision, text, tabular and
collaborative filtering.
We'll be learning about all of them and a
lot more.
For each one, say here's vision, you can import
from the .all, kind of meta-model, I guess
we could call it.
And that will give you all the stuff that
you need for most common vision applications.
So, if you're using a REPL system like Jupyter
notebook, it's going to give you all the stuff
right there that you need without having to
go back and figure it out.
One of the issues with this is a lot of the
python users don't.
If they look at something like untar_data,
they would figure out where it comes from
by looking at the import line.
And so if you import star, you can't do that
anymore.
The good news, in a REPL, you don't have to.
You can literally just type the symbol, press
SHIFT - ENTER and it will tell you exactly
where it came from.
As you can see.
So that's super handy.
So in this case, for example, to do the actual
building of the dataset, we called ImageDataLoaders.from_name_func.
I can actually call the special doc function
to get the documentation for that.
As you can see, it tells me exactly everything
to pass in, what all the defaults are, and
most importantly, not only what it does, but
SHOW IN DOCS pops me over to the full documentation
including an example.
Everything in the fastAI documentation has
an example and the cool thing is: the entire
documentation is written in Jupyter Notebooks.
So that means you can actually open the Jupyter
Notebook for this documentation and run the
line of code yourself and see it actually
working and look at the outputs and so forth.
Also in the documentation, you'll find that
there are a bunch of tutorials.
For example, if you look at the vision tutorial,
it will cover lots of things but one of the
things we will cover is, as you can see in
this case, pretty much the same kind of stuff
we are actually looking at in Lesson 1.
So there is a lot of documentation in fastAI
and taking advantage of it is a pretty good
idea.
It is fully searchable and as I mentioned,
perhaps most importantly, every one of these
documentation pages is also a fully interactive
Jupyter Notebook.
So, looking through more of this code, the
first line after the import is something that
uses untar_ data.
That will download a dataset, decompress it,
and put it on your computer.
If it is already downloaded, it won't download
it again.
If it is already decompressed it won't decompress
And as you can see, fastAI already has predefined
access to a number of really useful datasets.
such as this PETS dataset.
Datasets are a super important part, as you
can imagine of deep learning.
We will be seeing lots of them.
And these are created by lots of heroes (and
heroines) who basically spend months or years
collating data that we can use to build these
models.
The next step is to tell fastAI what this
data is and we will be learning a lot about
that.
But in this case, we are basically saying,
‘okay, it contains images'.
It contains images that are in this path.
So untar_data returns the path that is whereabouts
it has been decompressed to.
Or if it is already decompressed, it tells
us where it was previously decompressed to.
We have to tell it things like ‘okay, what
images are actually in that path'.
One of the really interesting ones is label_func.
How do you tell, for each file, whether it
is a cat or a dog.
And if you actually look at the ReadME for
the original dataset, it uses a slightly quirky
thing which is they said, ‘oh, anything
where the first letter of the filename is
an uppercase is a cat'.
That's what they decided.
So we just created a little function here
called is_cat that returns the first letter,
is it uppercase or not.
And we tell fastai that's how you tell if
it's a cat.
We'll come back to these two in a moment.
So the next thing, now we've told it what
the data is.
We then have to create something called a
learner.
A learner is a thing that learns, it does
the training.
So you have to tell it what data to use.
Then you have to tell it what architecture
to use.
I'll be talking a lot about this in the course.
But, basically, there's a lot of predefined
neural network architectures that have certain
pros and cons.
And for computer vision, the architecture
is called ResNet.
Just a super great starting point, and so
we're just going to use a reasonably small
one of them.
So these are all predefined and set up for
you.
And then you can tell fastai what things you
want to print out as it's training.
And in this case, we're saying “oh, tell
us the error, please, as you train”.
So then we can call this really important
method called fine_tune that we'll be learning
about in the next lesson which actually does
the training.
valid_pct does something very important.
It grabs, in this case, 20% of the data (.2
proportion), and does not use it for training
a model.
Instead, it uses it for telling you the error
rate of the model.
So, always in fastai this metric, error_rate,
will always be calculated on a part of the
data which has not been trained with.
And the idea here, and we'll talk a lot about
more about this in future lessons.
But the basic idea here is we want to make
sure that we're not overfitting.
Let me explain.
Overfitting looks like this.
Let's say you're trying to create a function
that fits all these dots, right.
A nice function would look like that, right.
But you could also fit, you can actually fit
it much more precisely with this function.
Look, this is going much closer to all the
dots than this one is.
So, this is obviously a better function.
Except, as soon as you get outside where the
dots are, especially if you go off the edges,
it's obviously doesn't make any sense.
So, this is what you'd call an overfit function.
So, overfitting happens for all kinds of reasons.
We use a model that's too big or we use not
enough data.
We'll be talking all about it, right.
But, really the craft of deep learning is
all about creating a model that has a proper
fit.
And the only way you know if a model has a
proper fit is by seeing whether it works well
on data that was not used to train it.
And so, we always set aside some of the data
to create something called a validation set.
The validation set is the data that we use
not to touch it at all when we're training
a model, but we're only using it to figure
out whether the model's actually working or
not.
One thing that Sylvain mentioned in the book,
is that one of the interesting things about
studying fastai is you learn a lot of interesting
programming practices.
And so I've been programming, I mean, since
I was a kid, so like 40 years.
And Sylvain and I both work really, really
hard to make python do a lot of work for us
and to use, you know, programming practices
which make us very productive and allow us
to come back to our code, years later and
still understand it.
And so you'll see in our code we'll often
do things that you might not have seen before.
And so we, a lot of students who have gone
through previous courses say they learned
a lot about coding and python coding and software
engineering from the course.
So, yeah check, when you see something new,
check it out and feel free to ask on the forums
if you're curious about why something was
done that way.
One thing to mention is, just like I mentioned
import star is something most Python programmers
don't do cause most libraries don't support
doing it properly.
We do a lot of things like that.
We do a lot of things where we don't follow
a traditional approach to python programming.
Because I've used so many languages over the
years, I code not in a way that's specifically
pythonic, but incorporates like ideas from
lots of other languages and lots of other
notations and heavily customised our approach
to python programming based on what works
well for data science.
That means that the code you see in fastai
is not probably, not gonna fit with, the kind
of style guides and normal approaches at your
workplace, if you use Python there.
So, obviously, you should make sure that you
fit in with your organization's programming
practices rather than following ours.
But perhaps in your own hobby work, you can
follow ours and see if you find that are interesting
and helpful, or even experiment with that
in your company if you're a manager and you
are interested in doing so.
Okay, so to finish, I'm going to show you
something pretty interesting, which is, have
a look at this code untar data, image data
loaders from name func, learner, fine tune.
Untar data, segmentation date loaders, from
label func, learner, fine tune.
Almost the same code, and this has built a
model that does something, whoa totally different!
It's something which has taken images.
This is on the left, this is the labeled data.
It's got images with color codes to tell you
whether it's a car, or a tree, or a building,
or a sky, or a line marking or a road.
And on the right is our model, and our model
has successfully figured out for each pixel,
is that a car, line marking, a road.
Now it's only done it in, under 20 seconds
right.
So it's a very small quick model.
It's made some mistakes -- like it's missing
this line marking, and some of these cars
it thinks is house, right?
But you can see so if you train this for a
few minutes, it's nearly perfect.
But you can see the basic idea is that we
can very rapidly, with almost exactly the
same code, create something not that classifies
cats and dogs but does what's called segmentation:
figures out what every pixel and image is.
Look, here's the same thing:
from import star
text loaders from folder
learner
learn fine-tune
Same basic code.
This is now something where we can give it
a sentence and it can figure out whether that
is expressing a positive or negative sentiment,
and this is actually giving a 93% accuracy
on that task in about 15 minutes on the IMDb
dataset, which contains thousands of full-length
movie reviews (in fact, 1000- to 3000-word
reviews).
This number here that we got with the same
three lines of code would have been the best
in the world for this task in a very, very,
very popular academics dataset in like 2015
I think.
So we are creating world-class models, in
our browser, using the same basic code.
Here's the same basic steps again:
from import star
untar data
tabular data loaders
from csv
learner fit
This is now building a model that is predicting
salary based on a csv table containing these
columns.
So this is tabular data.
Here's the same basic steps
from import *
untar data
collab data loaders from csv
learner fine-tune
This is now building something which predicts,
for each combination of a user and a movie,
what rating do we think that user will give
that movie, based on what other movies they've
watched and liked in the past.
This is called collaborative filtering and
is used in recommendation systems.
So here you've seen some examples of each
of the four applications in fastai.
And as you'll see throughout this course,
the same basic code and also the same basic
mathematical and software engineering concepts
allow us to do vastly different things using
the same basic approach.
And the reason why is because of Arthur Samuel.
Because of this basic description of what
it is you can do if only you have a way to
parameterize a model and you have an update
procedure which can update the weights to
make you better at your loss function, and
in this case we can use neural networks, which
are totally flexible functions.
So that's it for this first lesson.
It's a little bit shorter than our other lessons
going to be and the reason for that is that
we are as I mentioned at the start of a global
pandemic here, or at least in the West (in
other countries they are much further into
it).
So we spent some time talking about that at
the start of the course and you can find that
video elsewhere.
So in the future lessons there will be more
on deep learning.
So, what I suggest you do over the next week,
before you work on the next lesson, is just
make sure that you can spin up a GPU server,
you can shut down when it's finished and that
you can run all of the code here and, as you
go through, see if this is using Python in
a way you recognise, use the documentation,
use that doc function, do some search on the
fastai doc, see what it does, see if you can
actually grab the fastai documentation notebooks
themselves and run them.
Just try to get comfortable, that you can
if you can know your way around.
Because the most important thing to do with
this style of learning, this top-down learning,
is to be able to run experiments and that
means you need to be able to run code.
So my recommendation is: don't move on until
you can run the code, read the chapter of
the book, and then go through the questionnaire.
We still got some more work to do about validation
sets and test sets and transfer learning.
So you won't be able to do all of it yet but
try to to all the parts you can, based on
what we've seen of the course so far.
Rachel, anything you want to add before we
go.
Okay, so thanks very much for joining us for
lesson one everybody and are really looking
forward to seeing you next time where we will
learn about transfer learning and then we
will move on to creating an actual production
version of an application that we can actually
put out on the Internet and you can start
building apps that you can show your friends
and they can start playing with.
Bye Everybody